Hi everyone, we have been talking about what AI can do for us recently, right?
嗨各位，最近我們一直在討論 AI 能為我們做什麼，對吧？
But today we want to change the angle to talk about how we should use it.
但今天我們想要改變角度，談談我們應該如何使用它。
Well, this is a very important one, but to be honest, the concept that is often overlooked by everyone is called cautiousness.
這是一個非常重要的議題，但說實話，一個經常被大家忽視的概念叫做謹慎。
This can be said to be the most important part of taking responsibility for using AI.
這可以說是負責任地使用 AI 最重要的部分。
You can think that using AI is like driving.
你可以認為使用 AI 就像開車一樣。
Our goal should not only be to drive from point A to point B at the fastest speed, right?
我們的目標不應該只是以最快速度從 A 點開到 B 點，對吧？
When driving, we will also consider safety, follow traffic rules, and also pay attention to whether our driving method will affect other people on the road at any time.
開車時，我們也會考慮安全，遵守交通規則，還要注意我們的駕駛方式是否會隨時影響道路上的其他人。
This is the core spirit of AI cautiousness.
這就是 AI 謹慎精神的核心。
It does not look at how powerful AI is, but at how we use AI.
它不是看 AI 有多強大，而是看我們如何使用 AI。
What we are looking for is a way to be more moral, safer, and make every interaction with AI very rigorous, transparent, and responsible.
我們要找的是一種更有道德、更安全的方式，讓每一次與 AI 的互動都非常嚴謹、透明和負責任。
So you see, a key change of mind is here.
所以你看，這裡有一個重要的思維轉變。
Most people think of the left side of the road when using AI.
大多數人在使用 AI 時想到的是道路的左邊。
How to get things done the most efficiently and quickly.
如何最高效、最快速地完成事情。
But the concept of cautiousness is to remind us that the right side of the road, that is, how you reach your goal, is actually as important as it is, or even more important.
但謹慎的概念是提醒我們道路的右邊，也就是你如何達到目標，其實和左邊一樣重要，甚至更重要。
Okay, so next we're going to explore this concept like this.
好的，所以接下來我們就要這樣來探討這個概念。
First, let's see what elements are missing in AI.
首先，我們來看看 AI 缺少什麼元素。
Then we will break the cautiousness into three pillars, which are creation, transparency, and deployment.
然後我們會將謹慎分解成三個支柱，分別是創建、透明和部署。
Finally, let's talk about what roles each of us can play inside.
最後，我們來談談我們每個人在其中可以扮演什麼角色。
Okay, the first part, the elements that AI lacks.
好的，第一部分，AI 缺少的元素。
Yes, we all know that AI is very good at completing tasks, but is that enough?
是的，我們都知道 AI 很擅長完成任務，但這夠嗎？
The core of cautiousness is to stop and think about it when we use AI.
謹慎的核心是當我們使用 AI 時停下來思考。
In addition to doing things, what I am doing now may also have a wider impact.
除了做事之外，我現在所做的事情可能還會產生更廣泛的影響。
This brings up a fundamental question that we all have to ask ourselves.
這提出了一個我們都必須問自己的根本問題。
Who could these things I created with AI possibly affect?
我用 AI 創建的這些東西可能會影響誰？
You see, this question is no longer just a technical matter.
你看，這個問題已經不只是一個技術問題了。
It directly relates to the social responsibility of each of us.
它直接關係到我們每個人的社會責任。
So how do we have a system to implement it?
那麼我們如何才能建立一個系統來實施它呢？
It's not that hard.
這並不難。
We can break it into three very clear steps, or three pillars.
我們可以將它分解成三個非常清晰的步驟，或者說三個支柱。
The first step is creation.
第一步是創建。
The second step is transparency.
第二步是透明。
The last step is deployment.
最後一步是部署。
Let's look at them one by one.
我們逐一來看。
Okay, the first pillar is creation.
好的，第一個支柱是創建。
Let's go back to the example of driving.
讓我們回到開車的例子。
It's a bit like you really have to carefully choose which car to drive before you go out.
有點像你在出門前真的必須仔細選擇要開哪輛車。
Then which lane do I want to take?
那麼我要走哪一條車道？
So at this stage of creation, we have to ask ourselves the key question.
所以在創建的這個階段，我們必須問自己一個關鍵問題。
That is, which AI should I use?
那就是我應該使用哪個 AI？
And how should I use it?
以及我應該如何使用它？
It's really not just about opening a web page,
這不只是打開網頁的問題，
but we need to be very conscious, even with some criticism, to make a choice.
但我們需要非常謹慎，即使有一些批評，也要做出選擇。
Because as you know, different tools may lead to completely different results.
因為正如你所知，不同的工具可能會導致完全不同的結果。
So before and after using AI, we should ask ourselves some key questions.
所以在使用 AI 前後，我們應該問自己一些關鍵問題。
For example, how is this system trained?
例如，這個系統是如何訓練的？
What data does it use?
它使用什麼資料？
How do I protect myself and other people's privacy?
我如何保護自己和他人的隱私？
More importantly, does my interaction with it meet my own values?
更重要的是，我與它的互動是否符合我自己的價值觀？
Let me give you a super practical example.
讓我給你一個非常實際的例子。
Before you paste the company's sensitive internal data directly to the AI assistant,
在你直接將公司的敏感內部資料貼到 AI 助手之前，
did you stop and think about whether this service's data protection policy is okay?
你有沒有停下來思考這項服務的資料保護政策是否可以？
Is your company really allowing you to do that?
你的公司真的允許你這樣做嗎？
Okay, next is the second spider, transparent.
好的，接下來是第二個原則，透明度。
Let's go back to the metaphor of driving.
讓我們回到駕駛的比喻。
It's kind of like you telling the passenger in the car,
這有點像你告訴車裡的乘客，
Hey, I'm using GPS right now.
嘿，我現在正在使用 GPS。
Or we're going to take this particular route later.
或者我們稍後會走這條特定的路線。
So when it comes to transparency, the core problem is actually very simple.
所以當涉及到透明度時，核心問題其實非常簡單。
That is, in the data that you have,
也就是說，在你擁有的資料中，
who needs to know that AI is also involved?
誰需要知道 AI 也參與其中？
This directly relates to whether we have entered the responsibility of the notice.
這直接關係到我們是否進入了通知的責任。
Keeping transparent is actually more than just following any rules.
保持透明實際上不僅僅是遵守任何規則。
More importantly, this is a way to maintain trust and respect in the relationship between people.
更重要的是，這是一種在人與人之間的關係中維持信任和尊重的方式。
When we openly admit that AI plays a role,
當我們公開承認 AI 發揮了作用時，
we can make everyone more honest and honest.
我們可以讓每個人更加誠實坦率。
For example, you used AI to help write a team proposal.
例如，你使用 AI 幫助撰寫團隊提案。
Then you take the initiative to tell your colleagues,
那麼你主動告訴你的同事，
Hey, I used AI to assist in some part of this report.
嘿，我用 AI 協助撰寫了這份報告的某些部分。
This way, your cooperation can be established on the basis of honesty.
這樣，你們的合作就可以建立在誠實的基礎上。
Everyone in the team is also working together under the same situation of communication, right?
團隊中的每個人也都在相同的溝通情況下工作，對吧？
Next, let's take a look at the last spider, transparent.
接下來，讓我們看看最後一個原則，責任。
Just like driving is going to take all the responsibility for its driving behavior,
就像駕駛人要對自己的駕駛行為承擔全部責任一樣，
we as AI users must also take all the responsibility for the final result of AI production.
我們作為 AI 用戶也必須對 AI 生成結果的最終結果承擔全部責任。
When you share the content of AI,
當你分享 AI 的內容時，
think about who should be responsible for its accuracy and whether it is appropriate.
要思考誰應該對其準確性和恰當性負責。
The answer is actually the team.
答案其實是你。
So at this stage of deployment,
所以在這個部署階段，
your responsibility includes that you have to take the final responsibility for the result.
你的責任包括你必須對結果承擔最終責任。
You have to go and check the facts and sources in person.
你必須親自檢查事實和資源。
You have to check if there are any potential prejudices in the content.
你必須檢查內容中是否存在任何潛在的偏見。
You also have to ensure the accuracy of the information and the right to use it.
你也必須確保信息的準確性和使用權。
In the end, it is the content shared for you
最後，你分享的內容
that is covered by AI.
是由 AI 涵蓋的。
Imagine a reporter using AI to help write a script.
想像一位記者使用 AI 來幫助撰寫腳本。
Before the article is published,
在文章發表之前，
he or she still has to go and check every fact and source in person
他或她仍然必須親自去檢查每個事實和來源
to make sure that the script meets the professional standards of the news.
以確保腳本符合新聞的專業標準。
This standard is exactly the same as writing a script from the beginning to the end.
這個標準與從頭到尾寫一個腳本完全相同。
There is no space for any discount.
沒有任何折扣的空間。
Finally, let's talk about the roles of each of us.
最後，讓我們談談我們各自的角色。
What should we do to become a reliable driver
我們應該做什麼才能成為可靠的推動者
and then create a healthier AI ecosystem together?
並一起創造一個更健康的 AI 生態系統？
So let's review it again.
所以讓我們再次回顧一下。
Please remember these three pillars.
請記住這三個支柱。
When you create, you have to be careful.
當你創作時，你必須要小心。
When you communicate, you have to be careful.
當你溝通時，你必須要小心。
I think we all hope that the future of AI is fair, safe, and beneficial to society.
我認為我們都希望 AI 的未來是公平、安全且對社會有益的。
And to achieve this goal,
而要實現這個目標，
the key is actually in the hands of each of us.
關鍵實際上掌握在我們每個人的手中。
Each of our actions, each of our choices,
我們的每一個行動，我們的每一個選擇，
are creating the future appearance of AI together.
都在共同塑造 AI 的未來面貌。
So finally, I would like to leave a word to everyone.
所以最後，我想給大家留下一句話。
The future appearance of AI is in the hands of each of us.
AI 的未來面貌掌握在我們每個人的手中。
The future appearance of AI is in the hands of us.
AI 的未來面貌掌握在我們的手中。
Finally, I would like to leave a word to everyone.
最後，我想給大家留下一句話。
The future appearance of AI is your responsibility.
AI 的未來面貌是你的責任。
So how do you choose to practice the sacred duty?
那麼你選擇如何實踐這神聖的職責呢？